[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d0", "question": "What does a \u201cseismograph\u201d measure?", "answer": "Motions of the ground", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4a", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madama Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b18a", "question": "Who attempted to assassinate US President Ronald Reagan in 1981?", "answer": "John Hinckley Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa9", "question": "On which island was Napoleon exiled in 1814?", "answer": "Elba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c3", "question": "Where was the first YouTube video filmed?", "answer": "In a zoo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe36b250ada16518afdc039", "question": "From which country did the troll doll originate?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aec", "question": "The Christmas carol \"One Horse Open Sleigh\" is better known under which title?", "answer": "Jingle Bells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7cfb7877e98cb97778a52", "question": "Knoxville, Tennessee sits on the bank of what river?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6aa0b20565ad31a57c80f", "question": "Who was the American Ambassador to the United Nations during the Cuba missle crisis?", "answer": "Adlai Stevenson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6007821ebd51d85e222ab653", "question": "What was the original title of Auguste Rodin's famous sculpture \"The Thinker\"?", "answer": "Inspired by Dante's\u00a0\"Inferno,\"\u00a0\"The Thinker\" was originally entitled\u00a0\"The Poet\"\u00a0and conceived as a representation of Dante.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fedd9146ce05a3942286d78", "question": "What was the name of the last game released as a physical cartridge for the Super Nintendo?", "answer": "\"Fire Emblem: Thracia 776\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cdb6ee347d002c297e4dd", "question": "What does the energiser bunny wear on his feet?", "answer": "Flip flops", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a98d361d1b4d384d5d692", "question": "Who starred in the role of Ben in the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Lorne Greene", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a77d", "question": "Which two countries border the Dead Sea?", "answer": "Israel and Jordan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b5", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Missouri?", "answer": "Jefferson City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c8", "question": "Who built the world's first free-standing geodesic dome in 1949?", "answer": "Buckminster Fuller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985c", "question": "In the movie \"Howl's Moving Castle\", Calcifer was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Billy Crystal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff1", "question": "Who became president after William McKinley was assassinated?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c3", "question": "On what island was Napoleon born?", "answer": "Corsica", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba06", "question": "What sport did George Bush Sr. play at Yale University?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbb", "question": "What was the first US city to have a public school system?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937ec2008d98002fdd633b7", "question": "Which singer's autobiography is titled \"Take It Like a Man\"?", "answer": "Boy George's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b201", "question": "What ship was commanded by William Bligh?", "answer": "Bounty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a350", "question": "What Russian city boasts the Hermitage Museum?", "answer": "St. Petersburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a64652ebb971c1417fba4", "question": "What is typically considered the largest island in the world?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd2", "question": "What TV show did \"The Facts of Life\" spin off from?", "answer": "Diff'rent Strokes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec85bdec223966ae8f8808", "question": "In the music world, who is the \"Godfather Of Grime\"?", "answer": "Wiley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0e7d469bb8041d07a060", "question": "When a chef puts out every ingredient needed to prepare a dish ahead of time, what is it called?", "answer": "Mise En Place", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d209bb53d1af65886505", "question": "Who played the role of the Grinch in the 2000 film \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049ac5cf93664eb104869a", "question": "Comic book writer and artist Jack Kirby, was given what name at birth?", "answer": "Jacob Kurtzberg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b48b749076251badbeaa5", "question": "Who was the oldest person to travel in space?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He was 77-years-old when he returned to space on the Space Shuttle Discovery's STS-95 mission.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e7e", "question": "What musician is the father of singer Norah Jones?", "answer": "Ravi Shanker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f2d", "question": "Which band member of Blind Melon died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Shannon Hoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a0", "question": "Mount Kosciuszko is located in which country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae952f574a5ce6b56b8251", "question": "Who recorded the albums \"Into the Fire\" and \"Waking Up the Neighbours\"?", "answer": "Bryan Adams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b127", "question": "In what city was the UN charter signed?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab959c86faa38a764be517", "question": "Before starting to produce cars in the late 1940s, what did SAAB originally manufacture?", "answer": "Aircrafts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594d05821a1c922dd1ac64a3", "question": "What is Ronald Biggs famous for?", "answer": "Being one of the \"Great Train Robbers\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51301ff04d658268c92d5", "question": "Where was Adolf Hitler born?", "answer": "Hitler was born in Braunau am Inn, a town in Austria-Hungary (present-day Austria)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9bb21364247bf200fb8a0", "question": "What year did the Bee Gees release the album \"Trafalgar\"?", "answer": "1971", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2a39c9bff04efae6d75d", "question": "Eric Arthur Blair was the real name of which author?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9d", "question": "How did Scarlett and Rhett\u2019s daughter die, in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Fell off a horse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef62c06ce05a3942286e5f", "question": "What was the name of the Beatles' first studio album?", "answer": "Please Please Me", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d7", "question": "Which famous BBC presenter goes by the name of Jezza?", "answer": "Jeremy Clarkson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c101", "question": "What is the official language of Austria?", "answer": "German", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015dfd6fe83fe1f2a824b81", "question": "Who wrote the first algorithm intended to be carried out by a machine?", "answer": "Ada Lovelace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d1159a4fea7fe947a22268", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a59d", "question": "What US state's southern border is marked by the original Mason Dixon Line?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5f", "question": "According to the poem, how many spectators saw Mighty Casey strike out?", "answer": "Five thousand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a577", "question": "Washington D.C. is located in which state?", "answer": "None, it is not part of any US state", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aef3", "question": "In what type of container was Lord Nelson\u2019s body returned to England?", "answer": "Cask/barrel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fedd8cb6ce05a3942286d74", "question": "Which NBA player has had a tattoo of the late Malcolm X on his left calf at least since 2012?", "answer": "Derrick Rose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb7", "question": "Who wrote the 1971 novel \"The Exorcist\"?", "answer": "William Peter Blatty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d9", "question": "What number does the roman numeral LXXX denote?", "answer": "80", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a54f", "question": "Which US state is home to the Klamath Mountains?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad9df61e748bb36357acde8", "question": "The City of Hot Coffee is in what US state?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a24f", "question": "Who replaced Ronnie James Dio in Black Sabbath?", "answer": "Ian Gillan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d99c808b8581f80b092b7", "question": "What soccer team won the 2017 FIFA Club World Cup?", "answer": "Real Madrid", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a692", "question": "Mount hotham is located in which country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0de8bfcbed638185eaa16", "question": "In which US state is Crater Lake found?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc3", "question": "Who was dipped by the heel in the River Styx to give him invulnerability?", "answer": "Achilles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f70bba9e54d890926f6d7", "question": "In which city is the majority of the Las Vegas Strip located?", "answer": "Paradise -- The majority of the 4.2-mile stretch of glittering lights is actually located in the neighboring town of Paradise.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e5", "question": "What was the Allie's code name for the \"D-Day\" invasion of Normandy?", "answer": "Operation Overlord", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c917", "question": "Hans Lippershey made the worlds first practical what?", "answer": "Telescope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab183cbaab681b09292188", "question": "Which racing team introduced a six-wheeled race car in 1974 and began racing it in 1976?", "answer": "Tyrrell Racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9d", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Dave\"?", "answer": "Kevin Kline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a958", "question": "Which European country replaced the Pound with the Euro?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e4dcfe83fe1f2a824bb8", "question": "Anubis, the God of Death, had the head of a what?", "answer": "Jackal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a688", "question": "Lake Mohave lies several miles south of what larger lake?", "answer": "Lake Mead", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067c20ff9c0647b50a806a", "question": "What mountain range does the Gotthard Base Tunnel pass through?", "answer": "The Alps", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a273", "question": "Who was the male star of the 1997 film \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "Leonardo DiCaprio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd6c97e83c707845b216e", "question": "When was the first Masters Tournament played?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6bf", "question": "What acid gives vinegar its smell and taste?", "answer": "Acetic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a6f", "question": "The musical \"My Fair Lady\" was based on what classic play?", "answer": "Pygmalion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa38", "question": "What is the capital of the Democratic Republic of Congo?", "answer": "Kinshasa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c7", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Bay State\"?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e9", "question": "What year did the Republic of South Sudan gain its independence?", "answer": "2011", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a67120565ad31a57c7d9", "question": "What is the name of the first nuclear-powered merchant ship?", "answer": "NS Savannah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cd40e06685cf15b733e9896", "question": "In fencing what is the name of the action when two fencers make physical contact with any part of their bodies (or hilts)?", "answer": "Corps-a-corps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b3e5e662d71a53650fe6", "question": "What was one of Franz Liszt's most notable talents?", "answer": "Ability to improvise", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d7", "question": "The \"pinna\" is the outer, visible part of what?", "answer": "The ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f4a5fa5fdd6dd25324e2", "question": "What is the capital of Central African Republic?", "answer": "Bangui", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c325", "question": "What does the acronym RPM stand for?", "answer": "Revolutions per minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bef8", "question": "Which two fruits are an anagram of each other?", "answer": "Lemon and melon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe25a30658e585fda9cfa44", "question": "What does the term \"au gratin\" mean when it comes to cooking?", "answer": "Covered with browned crust, often breadcrumbs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae2e", "question": "Who is widely credited for sewing the first American flag?", "answer": "Betsy Ross", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca5d", "question": "Which flower is also known as the \"Lent Lily\"?\u00a0", "answer": "The daffodil", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6000ed369a72b906b34e3cea", "question": "Which scientist formulated the law of universal gravitation?", "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d47", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Empire Records\"?", "answer": "Robin Tunney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3fbec73aa70ea0b70b03", "question": "For the film \"The Empire Strikes Back,\" where were scenes set on the ice planet Hoth actually filmed?", "answer": "The Battle of Hoth scenes were shot on Handangerjokulen Glacier near the village of Finse, Norway.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f164eb8f9b80650dbe7f937", "question": "What color is the \"Reality stone\" in the 2017 Marvel Legacy relaunch?", "answer": "Red", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f62", "question": "What two Top Ten Creedence Clearwater Revival hits ask about the rain?", "answer": "\"Have You Ever Seen the Rain\" and \"Who'll Stop the Rain\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008ddb0f4f3bc4a292f8623", "question": "After World War II, who was the first leader of the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia?", "answer": "Ivan Ribar (From December 29. 2945 until January 14, 1953, he was the President of the Federal Assembly of Yugoslavia.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b457", "question": "What was the name of Hannibal's father?", "answer": "Hamilcar Barca", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c716", "question": "What astronomical unit of distance equals about 5.88 trillion miles?", "answer": "1 light year", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9bb", "question": "The zodiac sign \"Capricorn\" refers to what animal?", "answer": "The goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0c0b469bb8041d07a04c", "question": "What is the official flower of Easter?", "answer": "White Lilly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5901d9e6709c1c34536e6ead", "question": "The fans of Taylor Swift are known as what?", "answer": "Swifties", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b0", "question": "What do the Scoville Heat Units indicate?", "answer": "The amount of capsaicin present", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a2c56c0f9723ab15cb46", "question": "Which volcano had the most powerful eruption of the 20th century?", "answer": "Novarupta volcano", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc8", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Passepartout?", "answer": "Phileas Fogg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7df4ff048f679a45ac03", "question": "Arachnophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Spiders", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a1e1e25b5a031299b74573f", "question": "Which present-day country in the Southern hemisphere did the Dutch reach in 1606?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b1bae662d71a53650fd3", "question": "What short novel did John Steinbeck originally call \"Something that Happened\"?", "answer": "\"Of Mice and Men\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c159", "question": "What is a Hurdy-Gurdy?", "answer": "Stringed instrument", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49e", "question": "Which European country is stereotypically associated with tulips, windmills and clogs?", "answer": "Holland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8e3", "question": "What is the Latin word for the liquid produced by the Ficus Elastica?", "answer": "Latex", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79e", "question": "How many moons does the planet Neptune have?", "answer": "14", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a527", "question": "Whidbey Island is the largest island in which state?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b73b", "question": "Retsina is a wine traditionally made in which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87e", "question": "What country was called the Gold Coast prior to its 1957 independence?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cfb0877e98cb97778a51", "question": "What does Machu Picchu translate to in English?", "answer": "Old mountain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ac", "question": "The Yukon River flows through which US state?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40d", "question": "What country is East Pakistan now known as?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde494bc6c6b019850c9a6e", "question": "What was the first Christian country in Africa?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5956425b803c1f1ebcc4a02c", "question": "Tim McGraw and Faith Hill won the Academy of Country Music\u2019s very first Vocal Event trophy in 1997 for what song?", "answer": "\"It\u2019s Your Love\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89d", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after a married couple?", "answer": "Curium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b4cae662d71a53650ff0", "question": "What literary genre is Edgar Allen Poe credited with starting?", "answer": "Crime novels", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c1", "question": "One of the Midwest's \"Quad Cities\" is named for what three-mile-long island in the Mississippi?", "answer": "Rock Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a603", "question": "What Australian state surrounds the city of Canberra?", "answer": "New South Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339111", "question": "What boxer appeared in the broadway musical \"Buck White\" in 1969?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394bb", "question": "Who played the role of Lamont Sanford in the TV show \"Sanford and Son\"?", "answer": "Desmond Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45c", "question": "Who succeeded Anthony Eden as Prime Minister in 1957?", "answer": "Harold Macmillan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b975", "question": "Which Birthsign spans the months of January and February?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3fecc73aa70ea0b70b05", "question": "Which international airport sits on an artificial island?", "answer": "Hong Kong International Airport", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399af", "question": "In the movie \"Basic Instinct\", Michael Douglas plays a cop in what city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec4", "question": "Who was famous for saying \"That's telling like it is\"?", "answer": "Howard Cosell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd55cec223966ae8f88d0", "question": "\"You\u2019re gonna need a bigger boat\" originated in what movie?", "answer": "\"Jaws\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a620", "question": "What aquifer provides water for Nebraska, Kansas and Oklahoma?", "answer": "Ogallala aquifer", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c1a49076251badbeacd", "question": "Which First Lady was the first born outside of America?", "answer": "Louisa Adams, the wife of John Quincy Adams, was born in London.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4a4e49076251badbeab3", "question": "The former ranch supply town of Pecos, Texas, was home to the first what?", "answer": "Rodeo -- First held in 1883, the West of the Pecos Rodeo is one of the oldest rodeos in both Texas and the U.S.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c028d22ea32143fcb1d3b56", "question": "Who wrote the play \"Heartbreak House: A Fantasia in the Russian Manner on English Themes\"?", "answer": "George Bernard Shaw", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a732", "question": "What river flows along the western border of Illinois?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a92", "question": "What is the station and platform number for the Hogwarts Express?", "answer": "King's Cross Station, Platform 9 3/4", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc47f6ce05a3942286f33", "question": "Who directed the film \"The Silence of the Lambs\"?", "answer": "Johnathan Demme", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febbbbb7e83c707845b214a", "question": "What special title does Anthony Hopkins possess in real life?", "answer": "Sir (Sir Anthony Hopkins was knighted by Queen Elizabeth in 1993, two years after the release of \"the Silence of the Lambs\".)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b1ec4fda37788a9a1db4", "question": "Which once-common disease was also known as the \"Great white plague\"?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fed2893ec223966ae8f890b", "question": "\"2001: A Space Odyssey\" features which artificially-intelligent computer?", "answer": "HAL 9000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc1100469bb8041d07a072", "question": "What is the correct plural of Keeshond?", "answer": "Keeshonden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133980f", "question": "What is rapper Drake's full name?", "answer": "Aubrey Drake Graham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a3346c0f9723ab15cb4b", "question": "What was Ronald Reagan\u2019s Secret Service code name?", "answer": "Rawhide", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1b", "question": "In which decade did the Wall Street crash lead to the Great Depression?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d3", "question": "Which US state, one of the original 13 colonies, has a flag featuring an anchor surrounded by 13 stars?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa9", "question": "What is Ronald Reagan's middle name?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cdcc1e347d002c297e4eb", "question": "President Richard Nixon called what songstress an \"Ambassador of Love\"?", "answer": "Pearl Baily", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338916", "question": "What fairy tale character has two ugly stepsister?", "answer": "Cinderella", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa22", "question": "What Surrey town is famed for its salts?", "answer": "Epsom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf5", "question": "What color hair does Sega character Sonic the Hedgehog have?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76f2aeec85e375820b2e3", "question": "Which two countries are on the southern border of Mexico?", "answer": "Guatemala and Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf7", "question": "How many hits does it take to sink the submarine in the game of \"Battleship\"?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f2", "question": "What is halite more commonly called?", "answer": "Rock salt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5be5815c5415ba52ed6f0ac0", "question": "Orthoepy is the study of what?", "answer": "Pronunciation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b27", "question": "What 1991 River Phoenix/Keanu Reeves film took its title from lyrics in a B-52's song?", "answer": "My Own Private Idaho", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b2", "question": "Who wrote the 1924 novel \"Beau Geste\"?", "answer": "P. C. Wren", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea429eff048f679a45ab7b", "question": "What kind of animal is a chukar?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abca", "question": "South Africa has water access to which ocean?", "answer": "Indian and Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a05", "question": "What former athlete plays Matthew McConaughey\u2019s father in the movie \"Failure to Launch\"?", "answer": "Terry Bradshaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb92", "question": "What American fast food chain is known as PFK in the Canadian province of Quebec?", "answer": "KFC", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a239", "question": "What was the name of the album Men at Work released in 1981?", "answer": "Business as Usual", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a57f90aac110e4167074", "question": "How many Imperial gallons would a firkin of beer contain?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb45", "question": "A hobbyist referred to as a \"numismatist\" studies or collects what?", "answer": "Coins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c426", "question": "What element is combined with iron to become steel?", "answer": "Carbon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa47b6ce05a3942286eb3", "question": "In the film \"Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom,\" what was the name of Jones' young Asian friend?", "answer": "Short Round", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea80adff048f679a45ac1b", "question": "What type of rock dominates Yosemite National Park?", "answer": "Granite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7f", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Abe Ravelstein in the novel \"Ravelstein\"?", "answer": "Allan Bloom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c145", "question": "What type of sport is Birling?", "answer": "Logrolling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339493", "question": "What does Phil do for a living in the movie \"Groundhog Day\"?", "answer": "He is a weatherman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddbe56ce05a3942286d95", "question": "What was the name of the movie that Elvis Presley made his film debut in?", "answer": "\"Love Me Tender\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c7", "question": "What is the name of Warren Beaty's famous sister?", "answer": "Shirley MacLaine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c009", "question": "In pool, what color is the eight ball?", "answer": "Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173d3a44491cbd7c5a17ac", "question": "What was the original name for the Grammy Award(s)? ", "answer": "Gramophone Award ", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b07", "question": "What Jane Austen novel was rewritten in 2009 to include zombies?", "answer": "Pride and Prejudice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3cc", "question": "Who invented the Gatling gun?", "answer": "Richard Jordan Gatling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba85", "question": "Who succeeded Tom Brokaw as anchor on NBC\u2019s Nightly News in 2004?", "answer": "Brian Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bed", "question": "What was the name of the sacred river in Samuel Taylor Coleridge's Xanadu?", "answer": "Alph", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b372", "question": "What was the name of the scandal that forced President Nixon to resign?", "answer": "Watergate\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e8f7fe83fe1f2a824be2", "question": "Which monarch appointed Pitt the Younger to the office of prime minister in December 1783?", "answer": "George III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338932", "question": "What is the given name of the famous German composer and pianist Beethoven?", "answer": "Ludwig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb675c5dad637d903c883d", "question": "According to its former minister of tourism, which country is known abroad for its three Rs: reggae, romance and running?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b323608bf195a31e15d73b5", "question": "What character was invented to respond to questions from Gold Medal Flour customers?", "answer": "Betty Crocker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339343", "question": "Who was the cook on the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Hop Sing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e00", "question": "Whose tombstone bears the inscription \"Everybody Loves Somebody Sometime\"?", "answer": "Dean Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7abd196490a8cc1a6e529d", "question": "In The Maze Runner, the \"killzone\" refers to what?", "answer": "The Brain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60136ff7138175489539637e", "question": "Singer/songwriter Dan Hartman's song, \"I Can Dream About You\", is on the soundtrack of what 1980s film?", "answer": "\"Streets of Fire\" -- The actors sing the song in the film, but Hartman sings it on the soundtrack and in the music video.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be3", "question": "In what year was actor Johnny Depp born?", "answer": "1963", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26a", "question": "Who took Barry Goldwater's seat when the longtime senator retired in 1986?", "answer": "John McCain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad9e1dae748bb36357acdf7", "question": "What previously Fox News anchor secured a show on NBC in 2017?", "answer": "Megyn Kelly (the show is Megyn Kelly Today)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c35f7815febcc896f9262", "question": "What firm made the B25 Micro Computer?", "answer": "Burroughs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc8", "question": "Which US state was an independent nation for ten years during the 19th century?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb08298cf631c2414a13b46", "question": "How many soccer players should each team typically hove on the field at the start of each match?", "answer": "11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f0d1fe83fe1f2a824c13", "question": "Which country hosted the first decorated Christmas tree?", "answer": "The first decorated Christmas tree was in Riga, Latvia in 1510.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984b", "question": "The music duo \"Daft Punk\" consists of which two French musicians?", "answer": "Thomas Bangalter and Guy-Manuel de Homem-Christo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84b", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the malleus?", "answer": "The ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65dbc1f3c0ead6880d620", "question": "What did God place at the east of the Garden of Eden after he drove out Adam and Eve?", "answer": "Cherubims", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c1", "question": "What CEO bounced back after being fired by Henry Ford II in 1978?", "answer": "Lee Iacocca", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe907dd01dd7bf43be5e882", "question": "What is often referred to as the most slippery substance in the world?", "answer": "Polytetrafluoroethene also known as Teflon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c73", "question": "What TV show features the fictional TV show \"When the Whistle Blows\"?", "answer": "Extras", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af54", "question": "In which battle was Nelson killed?", "answer": "Battle of Trafalgar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133955e", "question": "Who is the star of the \"Tomb Raider\" video games?", "answer": "Lara Croft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a636", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Sunshine State\"?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76f", "question": "A \"brigantine\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Sailing ship", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f33", "question": "Which band member of Red Hot Chili Peppers died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Hillel Slovak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f7", "question": "What gender are whiptail lizards?", "answer": "Female", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339370", "question": "What movie won the Oscar for Best Visual Effects in 1978?", "answer": "Superman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23e", "question": "What is the more common name for an Apiarist?", "answer": "Beekeeper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121c4463c99d48cd169b14", "question": "What was the subject of most Norman Rockwell paintings?", "answer": "Everyday life -- His images captured not only the events of daily life, but what they meant to people of the time.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c883", "question": "What popular computer language shares its name with the vitamin formerly known as ascorbic acid?", "answer": "C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6012188763c99d48cd169af4", "question": "What flavor is Cointreau?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bc84d96d05b23b281656", "question": "Who captured and murdered the Inca Emperor Atahualpa?", "answer": "Francisco Pizarro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c5", "question": "What island is Tokyo located on?", "answer": "Honshu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9b", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"And Outcast of the Islands\"?", "answer": "Joseph Conrad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c007", "question": "Parasitophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Parasites", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbaf", "question": "In karate, what color belt is earned just before black?", "answer": "Brown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6bbd0fb6c85e9e634ff59", "question": "What is the word \"laser\" short for?", "answer": "Light amplification by stimulated emission of radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba09", "question": "Who won 7 gold medals in swimming at the 1972 Summer Olympics in Munich?", "answer": "Mark Spitz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c397877e98cb97778996", "question": "Where is the natural gas-burning \"Fire Mountain\" located?", "answer": "Azerbaijan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afa", "question": "The movies \"Black Hawk Down\", \"Blade Runner\", and \"Gladiator\" were all directed by whom?", "answer": "Ridley Scott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c8610775fa611bce67de", "question": "What instrument's name literally translates as \"jumping flea\"?", "answer": "Ukulele -- Meaning \"jumping flea\" in Hawaiian, the ukulele is about as closely linked to the island state as leis and the hula.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c46d", "question": "What color is a huckleberry?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd9", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"X\"?", "answer": "Xray", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b373", "question": "What country's explorers discovered the site of Pensacola, Florida?", "answer": "Spain's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ade", "question": "In 1996, what action star was named a \"sacred vessel\" of Tibetan Buddhism?", "answer": "Steven Seagal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b468", "question": "What year did Ferdinand Porsche and his team started to design the VW Beetle?", "answer": "1934", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6f", "question": "What are described by the terms rep, challis and foulard?", "answer": "Neckties", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bd", "question": "What is measured in Newtons?", "answer": "Force", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbd535000d154d7af00b8dc", "question": "Which band recorded and released the song\"Cotton Eye Joe\"?", "answer": "Rednex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fff6a4edfd43a087add6", "question": "Whose painting \"Irises\" was sold to Alan Bond in 1987?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f1648d3f9b80650dbe7f928", "question": "What Disney movie was the song \"Speechless\" featured in?", "answer": "Aladdin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa7", "question": "Frank Zappa's 1979 album \"Sheik Yerboutti\" was a salute to what band's 1976 hit?", "answer": "KC and the Sunshine Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f42001dd7bf43be5e81e", "question": "In computers, DAEMON stands for what?", "answer": "Disk And Execution Monitor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba395874c93a3298b213d", "question": "Who was nicknamed La Pucelle d'Orl\u00e9ans?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c268", "question": "What is the common name for hydrogen hydroxide?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0df", "question": "In what year was the \"Star Spangled Banner\" designated the US National Anthem?", "answer": "1931", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd0", "question": "What NBA star made an ill-fated trip to Eagle, Colorado, in 2003 for knee surgery?", "answer": "Kobe Bryant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a421", "question": "What is the world's highest waterfall?", "answer": "Angel Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d91", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Clifford Harris?", "answer": "T.I.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c2f", "question": "Who voiced Snow White in the 1937 movie \"Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs\"?", "answer": "Adriana Caselotti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd703e347d002c297e4be", "question": "Which pioneer of modern nursing had a cat called Bismark?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a8", "question": "\"Sphenopalatine Ganglioneuralgia\" is commonly referred to as?", "answer": "Brain freeze", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecdd4fec223966ae8f8904", "question": "Where was golf's Vijay Singh born?", "answer": "Fiji", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910a", "question": "What year was Viktor Frankl's book \"Man's Search for Meaning\" published?", "answer": "1946", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cff", "question": "In which movie did Cassandra Gava portray a witch?", "answer": "Conan the Barbarian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f48501dd7bf43be5e822", "question": "What are Klupskies?", "answer": "Polish burgers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0c1b469bb8041d07a04d", "question": "\"Open Your Hand And Smile\" has been which product's ad slogan?", "answer": "M&M\"s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae8", "question": "When was the Christmas carol \"Silent Night\" composed?", "answer": "1818", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922a", "question": "What Welsh songstress has performed the themes for three different Bond movies?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e6", "question": "What do most tourists call the Vieux Carre?", "answer": "The French Quarter", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c875", "question": "What type of animal are flying foxes?", "answer": "Bats", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf2", "question": "What was the official name for the World War II evacuation of Dunkirk?", "answer": "Operation Dynamo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592eada3f83302ff91e4647f", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Nebraska?", "answer": "Lincoln", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f4", "question": "What is considered as the first daily comic strip in the US?", "answer": "Mutt and Jeff", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c78c", "question": "By what common name do we refer to \"hook and loop\" fasteners as?", "answer": "Velcro", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc62", "question": "What is depicted on a traditional \"Jolly Roger\" flag?", "answer": "Skull and Crossbones", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fac", "question": "What TV title character lived at 485 Mapleton Drive, Mayfield?", "answer": "Beaver Cleaver", "category": "entertainment"}]